<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on wickedlyethan</title>
    <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on wickedlyethan</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024-04-06</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-04-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-04-06/</guid>
      <content>I know Marvel Discourse is considered indescribably lame, but I&amp;rsquo;m watching Captain America: Civil War (2016) because I got it on 4k for very little, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to say about these early Russo brothers films! The techno-thriller vibes, the nasty and up-close fight and stunt choreography, the centering of two deeply flawed men as the protagonists/id/ego of all superheroes in general. It&amp;rsquo;s both really damn good and already so Of Its Time already (oh gods it&amp;rsquo;s almost ten years old ugh).
      
      </content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-04-01</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-04-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-04-01/</guid>
      <content>Similar to making your phone grayscale, stripping out the colors and fluff from important interfaces can be a great way to figure out what you really need and expose the bullshit for what it is. Enter 68k.news: Headlines From the Future, one of my favorite low-tech websites. It&amp;rsquo;s literally Google News but stripped of all its styling and images, for good and bad: every news item still gets multiple sources, but those sources are frequently corporate dogshit.
      
      </content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-04-01_2</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2/</guid>
      <content>I deleted my Reddit account a few months ago now, but I can&amp;rsquo;t stop going on Reddit. I check r/all like a fool, and I check r/popular like a sheep; what&amp;rsquo;s missing from both is most of the good stuff on Reddit, meaning the smaller communities you joined for in the first place. So I&amp;rsquo;m glad I learned about the beautifully basic functionality of a multireddit – it&amp;rsquo;s just a long URL with the subs you want, such as &amp;ldquo;reddit.
      
      </content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-03-31</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-03-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-03-31/</guid>
      <content>Perfect Days (2023) is an instant favorite for me and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I got to see it a cinema over the weekend. The appreciation of beautiful, simple things –especially nature, even in a megalopolis; the thoughtful and considerate design of Tokyo&amp;rsquo;s public restrooms and other communal resources; the minimalist, utilitarian fashion; the warmth and tactile nature of physical media; remembering that every day can be a perfect day, if you think about it the right way.
      
      </content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-03-18</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-03-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-03-18/</guid>
      <content>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to keep my phone away from the bed for years, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been blocked by the dumbest, should-be-simplest functionality: alarms. Standard alarm clocks are totally inflexible; my Fitbit has a Smart Wake functionality, but it&amp;rsquo;s centered around the time you set for the alarm. Only the horribly named, very Android-core Sleep as Android has what I would consider the correct way to do things: You tell the app when you&amp;rsquo;re going to sleep and it sets an alarm, monitors your sleep state, then gently wakes you within a 30 minute window of the alarm.
      
      </content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-03-17</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-03-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-03-17/</guid>
      <content>I&amp;rsquo;ll probably write a proper post about this at some point, but in &amp;ldquo;launching&amp;rdquo; yet another new design for my site (hopefully this one will stick, I actually built it for content, now I just need to make content!) I looked at tons of inspiration. Here&amp;rsquo;s some of it: the Own Your Website newsletter by Matthias Ott, Dead Simple Sites by Arcade Labs, &amp;ldquo;100 things you can do on your personal website&amp;rdquo; by James Coffee, and of course my dear friend nathan wentworth&amp;rsquo;s personal site.
      
      </content>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
