<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>All Blog Posts on </title>
    <link>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in All Blog Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ethanthibault.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Argylle is One of the Worst Movies I’ve Ever Seen</title>
      <link>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/argylle-is-really-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/argylle-is-really-bad/</guid>
      <description>The first red flag was Henry Cavill&amp;rsquo;s haircut in the trailer. The second red flag, also from the trailer, was the obnoxious title card &amp;ldquo;FROM THE TWISTED MIND OF MATTHEW VAUGN&amp;rdquo;. The third red flag was this BBC One interview where the venerable Ali Plumb tries his best to find anything to talk about but can&amp;rsquo;t because of all supposed twists and turns of this &amp;ldquo;meta&amp;rdquo; spy adventure.
That video is what made me want to spend a Bargain Tuesday seeing it, ironically, because surely this cast is so charming, that&amp;rsquo;ll be enough, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media of the Year 2023</title>
      <link>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2023-12-29-media-of-the-year-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2023-12-29-media-of-the-year-2023/</guid>
      <description>Books Prayer for the Crown-Shy by Becky Chambers I was trying to be good and write about books that came out this year - striving to be contemporary, for once - but I have to, and must, talk about this book.
I&amp;rsquo;m deeply jealous at how amazing a writer Becky Chambers is, but the truth is it is a privilege to get to read books this good. Every work of hers I&amp;rsquo;ve read - To be Taught, if Fortunate, A Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet, and A Psalm for the Wild-Built - have instantly become not only favorites of mine, but texts to turn to in bad times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023 is the Wettest Year in Movies</title>
      <link>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2023-12-06-2023-is-the-wettest-year-in-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2023-12-06-2023-is-the-wettest-year-in-movies/</guid>
      <description>Last night I saw James Cameron&amp;rsquo;s stunning technical achievement and &amp;ldquo;grandiose weepie&amp;rdquo; The Abyss, originally released in 1989 and now finally remastered in 4k and put into theaters for a one-night IMAX showing, cementing 2023 as the wettest year in movies ever.
Matt Patches at Polygon called it back in November 2022, but with the year closing out with Aquaman: The Lost Kingdom for some reason, the trend is undeniable. Black Panther: Wakanda Forever, The Little Mermaid, John Wick: Chapter 4, Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny, Meg 2: The Trench, Godzilla Minus One - major releases this year included tense encounters with the big blue, actors soaked to the bone for their stunts, or contemplating the rain and its chain reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Film Scores of 2023</title>
      <link>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2023-11-16-my-favorite-film-scores-of-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2023-11-16-my-favorite-film-scores-of-2023/</guid>
      <description>Before we begin, special mention has to be made of the soundtrack for the existential comedy that surprised us all, Barbie. The score by Mark Ronson and Andrew Wyatt is playful but smartly gets out of the way of the exuberant cast. Barbie the Album, meanwhile is full of head-spinning delights that are essential to the film and can&amp;rsquo;t be separated. The height of the hopefully-timeless pop hits is Dua Lipa&amp;rsquo;s disco Greek chorus &amp;ldquo;Dance the Night&amp;rdquo;, which includes this, the correct Mood verse of 2023:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media of the Year 2022</title>
      <link>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2023-01-01-media-retrospective-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2023-01-01-media-retrospective-2022/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re back doing one of these! A surprisingly earnest year with lots of adventure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Blue Hill</title>
      <link>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2021-11-23-the-great-blue-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2021-11-23-the-great-blue-hill/</guid>
      <description>Thanksgiving as a holiday has been having a slow-motion reckoning over the years, somewhat alongside Columbus in all of his fuckery. In celebration, in a friend&amp;rsquo;s Discord server someone casually dropped Native Land Digital, a not-for-profit that superimposes indigenous nation territories onto the world as we definitely don&amp;rsquo;t know it today, without standard state and country borders and topographical information only.
Being from Massachusetts I&amp;rsquo;ve always been surrounded by Indigenous American culture in the exact way that makes it sadly invisible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media of the Year 2019</title>
      <link>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2019-12-28-media-retrospective-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2019-12-28-media-retrospective-2019/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s right, we&amp;rsquo;re doing one of these EVERY year. Featuring: communist witches, superhero ennui, hot scots, and the answer to what part of you your cat will eat first when you die.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media of the Year 2018</title>
      <link>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2018-12-28-media-retrospective-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2018-12-28-media-retrospective-2018/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll never remember everything, and there&amp;rsquo;s little things that I can&amp;rsquo;t fit into these categories, but here&amp;rsquo;s a retrospective of all the input I took in this year, all the thoughts I let invade my head to try and quiet it down a little bit, or conversely, wake up from a deep dream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Sea of Thieves&#39; Let Me Turn Into a Monster for a Weekend</title>
      <link>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2018-03-13-sea-of-thieves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2018-03-13-sea-of-thieves/</guid>
      <description>My family on my dad&amp;rsquo;s side are a bunch of nautical nerds. When Rare announced &amp;ldquo;Sea of Thieves&amp;rdquo; a while ago, my interest piqued immediately, and with the opportunity to jump into the &amp;ldquo;final beta&amp;rdquo; over the weekend I got some of what I always wanted, but also a bunch that I didn&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Life is Too Beautiful to Use Shitty Headphones</title>
      <link>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2024-03-01-your-life-is-too-beautiful-to-use-shitty-headphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ethanthibault.com/blog/2024-03-01-your-life-is-too-beautiful-to-use-shitty-headphones/</guid>
      <description>The average person listens to between two and four hours of music a day. Then there&amp;rsquo;s podcasts and audiobooks, YouTube videos, phone calls - we listen to so much stuff all the time, yet most people simply don&amp;rsquo;t care about how they listen to stuff and that makes me sad.
Wired earbuds returned for a moment in 2021 so TikTok makers could whisper dramatically into the in-line microphone, but this one random report points to the &amp;ldquo;true wireless stereo earbuds market&amp;rdquo; reaching $243.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
