<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wickedlyethan</title>
    <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on wickedlyethan</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wickedlyethan.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024-04-17</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-04-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-04-17/</guid>
      <description>Learning more about the death of VICE baffles and angers me in turn. One never got the impression they were a well-run company – a nonsensical TV strategy threw a lot of their judgement into question – but finding out that the whole enterprise was Shane Smith&amp;rsquo;s piggy bank sucks. Like Buzzfeed and its sister publication Buzzfeed News, VICE News was an award-winning, influential, and fearless group of journalists doing important work paid for by cringe shitposting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EVERYBODY Loves Pinball</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2024/04/everyone-loves-pinball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2024/04/everyone-loves-pinball/</guid>
      <description>Playing games in public is back, and pinball is the oldest instutition around, and there was nowhere better to be than Pintastic New England on a Friday night. The other good news about pinball is that it&amp;rsquo;s everywhere – pinball appears to have had a resurgence during the pandemic, like many vintage forms of gaming, and shows like Pintastic will only get bigger.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oops I Re-Did My Stylesheet Again</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2024/04/oops-i-re-did-my-stylesheet-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2024/04/oops-i-re-did-my-stylesheet-again/</guid>
      <description>Having no archive and habitually erasing all the evidence anwyays, it might not be obvious that I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of person who redesigns their website every 6 months to a year. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a personal website since middle school in one form or another - Blogger, Wordpress, Tumblr, then in college hand-crafted, deeply amateur HTML. We&amp;rsquo;re way past the ship of Theseus at this point, past sports car getting rebuilt in the garage; it&amp;rsquo;s some kind of mania.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-04-06</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-04-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-04-06/</guid>
      <description>I know Marvel Discourse is considered indescribably lame, but I&amp;rsquo;m watching Captain America: Civil War (2016) because I got it on 4k for very little, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to say about these early Russo brothers films! The techno-thriller vibes, the nasty and up-close fight and stunt choreography, the centering of two deeply flawed men as the protagonists/id/ego of all superheroes in general. It&amp;rsquo;s both really damn good and already so Of Its Time already (oh gods it&amp;rsquo;s almost ten years old ugh).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-04-01</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-04-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-04-01/</guid>
      <description>Similar to making your phone grayscale, stripping out the colors and fluff from important interfaces can be a great way to figure out what you really need and expose the bullshit for what it is. Enter 68k.news: Headlines From the Future, one of my favorite low-tech websites. It&amp;rsquo;s literally Google News but stripped of all its styling and images, for good and bad: every news item still gets multiple sources, but those sources are frequently corporate dogshit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-04-01_2</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2/</guid>
      <description>I deleted my Reddit account a few months ago now, but I can&amp;rsquo;t stop going on Reddit. I check r/all like a fool, and I check r/popular like a sheep; what&amp;rsquo;s missing from both is most of the good stuff on Reddit, meaning the smaller communities you joined for in the first place. So I&amp;rsquo;m glad I learned about the beautifully basic functionality of a multireddit – it&amp;rsquo;s just a long URL with the subs you want, such as &amp;ldquo;reddit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-03-31</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-03-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-03-31/</guid>
      <description>Perfect Days (2023) is an instant favorite for me and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I got to see it a cinema over the weekend. The appreciation of beautiful, simple things –especially nature, even in a megalopolis; the thoughtful and considerate design of Tokyo&amp;rsquo;s public restrooms and other communal resources; the minimalist, utilitarian fashion; the warmth and tactile nature of physical media; remembering that every day can be a perfect day, if you think about it the right way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dopamine Was Never Enough</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2024/03/dopamine-was-never-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2024/03/dopamine-was-never-enough/</guid>
      <description>In the latest issue of The Convival Society, L.M. Sacasas responds to Ted Gioia&amp;rsquo;s essay &amp;ldquo;The State of the Culture, 2024&amp;rdquo;, and they both have interesting thoughts on distraction and technology use. I like both and also disagree with them, and I wanted to get some thoughts down.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the source essay first. Gioia, in his frank style, makes the argument that distraction is subsuming all other forms of culture, and that the peddlers of said distraction are a &amp;ldquo;dopamine cartel&amp;rdquo;, solely focused on creating users who are addicted to the low-quality content on their platforms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-03-18</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-03-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-03-18/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to keep my phone away from the bed for years, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been blocked by the dumbest, should-be-simplest functionality: alarms. Standard alarm clocks are totally inflexible; my Fitbit has a Smart Wake functionality, but it&amp;rsquo;s centered around the time you set for the alarm. Only the horribly named, very Android-core Sleep as Android has what I would consider the correct way to do things: You tell the app when you&amp;rsquo;re going to sleep and it sets an alarm, monitors your sleep state, then gently wakes you within a 30 minute window of the alarm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-03-17</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-03-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/notes/2024-03-17/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll probably write a proper post about this at some point, but in &amp;ldquo;launching&amp;rdquo; yet another new design for my site (hopefully this one will stick, I actually built it for content, now I just need to make content!) I looked at tons of inspiration. Here&amp;rsquo;s some of it: the Own Your Website newsletter by Matthias Ott, Dead Simple Sites by Arcade Labs, &amp;ldquo;100 things you can do on your personal website&amp;rdquo; by James Coffee, and of course my dear friend nathan wentworth&amp;rsquo;s personal site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-03-14</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/photos/2024-03-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/photos/2024-03-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wickedlyethan.com/images/photos/2024-03-14-16h15m12.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mass Audubon&amp;rsquo;s Rocky Hill Wildlife Sanctuary&#34; title=&#34;Mass Audubon&#39;s Rocky Hill Wildlife Sanctuary&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-03-06</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/photos/2024-03-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/photos/2024-03-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wickedlyethan.com/images/photos/2024-02-14-17h27m49.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ARLO&#34; title=&#34;Arlo!!!&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Life is Too Beautiful to Use Shitty Headphones</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2024/03/your-life-is-too-beautiful-to-use-shitty-headphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2024/03/your-life-is-too-beautiful-to-use-shitty-headphones/</guid>
      <description>The average person listens to between two and four hours of music a day. Then there&amp;rsquo;s podcasts and audiobooks, YouTube videos, phone calls - we listen to so much stuff all the time, yet most people simply don&amp;rsquo;t care about how they listen to stuff and that makes me sad.&#xA;Wired earbuds returned for a moment in 2021 so TikTok makers could whisper dramatically into the in-line microphone, but this one random report points to the &amp;ldquo;true wireless stereo earbuds market&amp;rdquo; reaching $243.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Argylle is One of the Worst Movies I’ve Ever Seen</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2024/02/argylle-is-really-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2024/02/argylle-is-really-bad/</guid>
      <description>The first red flag was Henry Cavill&amp;rsquo;s haircut in the trailer. The second red flag, also from the trailer, was the obnoxious title card &amp;ldquo;FROM THE TWISTED MIND OF MATTHEW VAUGN&amp;rdquo;. The third red flag was this BBC One interview where the venerable Ali Plumb tries his best to find anything to talk about but can&amp;rsquo;t because of all supposed twists and turns of this &amp;ldquo;meta&amp;rdquo; spy adventure.&#xA;That video is what made me want to spend a Bargain Tuesday seeing it, ironically, because surely this cast is so charming, that&amp;rsquo;ll be enough, right?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Media of the Year 2023</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2023/12/media-of-the-year-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2023/12/media-of-the-year-2023/</guid>
      <description>Books Prayer for the Crown-Shy by Becky Chambers I was trying to be good and write about books that came out this year - striving to be contemporary, for once - but I have to, and must, talk about this book.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m deeply jealous at how amazing a writer Becky Chambers is, but the truth is it is a privilege to get to read books this good. Every work of hers I&amp;rsquo;ve read - To be Taught, if Fortunate, A Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet, and A Psalm for the Wild-Built - have instantly become not only favorites of mine, but texts to turn to in bad times.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 is the Wettest Year in Movies</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2023/12/2023-is-the-wettest-year-in-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2023/12/2023-is-the-wettest-year-in-movies/</guid>
      <description>Last night I saw James Cameron&amp;rsquo;s stunning technical achievement and &amp;ldquo;grandiose weepie&amp;rdquo; The Abyss, originally released in 1989 and now finally remastered in 4k and put into theaters for a one-night IMAX showing, cementing 2023 as the wettest year in movies ever.&#xA;Matt Patches at Polygon called it back in November 2022, but with the year closing out with Aquaman: The Lost Kingdom for some reason, the trend is undeniable. Black Panther: Wakanda Forever, The Little Mermaid, John Wick: Chapter 4, Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny, Meg 2: The Trench, Godzilla Minus One - major releases this year included tense encounters with the big blue, actors soaked to the bone for their stunts, or contemplating the rain and its chain reactions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Film Scores of 2023</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2023/11/my-favorite-film-scores-of-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2023/11/my-favorite-film-scores-of-2023/</guid>
      <description>Before we begin, special mention has to be made of the soundtrack for the existential comedy that surprised us all, Barbie. The score by Mark Ronson and Andrew Wyatt is playful but smartly gets out of the way of the exuberant cast. Barbie the Album, meanwhile is full of head-spinning delights that are essential to the film and can&amp;rsquo;t be separated. The height of the hopefully-timeless pop hits is Dua Lipa&amp;rsquo;s disco Greek chorus &amp;ldquo;Dance the Night&amp;rdquo;, which includes this, the correct Mood verse of 2023:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023-10-19</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/photos/2023-10-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/photos/2023-10-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wickedlyethan.com/images/photos/2023-10-19-16h56m36.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;landscape photograph at Prospect Hill in Harvard, Massachusetts&#34; title=&#34;Prospect Hill lookout in Harvard, MA&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Media of the Year 2022</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2023/01/media-retrospective-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2023/01/media-retrospective-2022/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re back doing one of these! A surprisingly earnest year with lots of adventure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Blue Hill</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2021/11/the-great-blue-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2021/11/the-great-blue-hill/</guid>
      <description>Thanksgiving as a holiday has been having a slow-motion reckoning over the years, somewhat alongside Columbus in all of his fuckery. In celebration, in a friend&amp;rsquo;s Discord server someone casually dropped Native Land Digital, a not-for-profit that superimposes indigenous nation territories onto the world as we definitely don&amp;rsquo;t know it today, without standard state and country borders and topographical information only.&#xA;Being from Massachusetts I&amp;rsquo;ve always been surrounded by Indigenous American culture in the exact way that makes it sadly invisible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Media of the Year 2019</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2019/12/media-retrospective-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2019/12/media-retrospective-2019/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s right, we&amp;rsquo;re doing one of these EVERY year. Featuring: communist witches, superhero ennui, hot scots, and the answer to what part of you your cat will eat first when you die.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Media of the Year 2018</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2018/12/media-retrospective-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2018/12/media-retrospective-2018/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll never remember everything, and there&amp;rsquo;s little things that I can&amp;rsquo;t fit into these categories, but here&amp;rsquo;s a retrospective of all the input I took in this year, all the thoughts I let invade my head to try and quiet it down a little bit, or conversely, wake up from a deep dream.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Sea of Thieves&#39; Let Me Turn Into a Monster for a Weekend</title>
      <link>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2018/03/sea-of-thieves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wickedlyethan.com/blog/2018/03/sea-of-thieves/</guid>
      <description>My family on my dad&amp;rsquo;s side are a bunch of nautical nerds. When Rare announced &amp;ldquo;Sea of Thieves&amp;rdquo; a while ago, my interest piqued immediately, and with the opportunity to jump into the &amp;ldquo;final beta&amp;rdquo; over the weekend I got some of what I always wanted, but also a bunch that I didn&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
